-谁要法国吐司   -我要
- Hey. Who wants French toast? - I'll have some.
我也要  牛奶和鸡蛋在冰箱里  谢谢
Me too. Eggs and milk in the fridge. Thanks.
-怎么了亲爱的  -我的手怪怪的
- What's the matter, honey? - My hand feels weird.
大概因为我订婚了
I guess it's because I'm engaged!
-什么时候这种笑话会开始变得烦人  -开始
- How long before that will start getting annoying? - Start?
开始计划婚礼吧
Let's just start the wedding plans.
-好  -现在
- Okay. - Already?
有很多事要做
Yeah, we got a lot to do.
要考虑鲜花  食物  音乐
We gotta think about the flowers, the caters, the music...
-我觉得音乐的安排  -钱德勒  已经很多计划了
- I have some thoughts on the music... - Chandler. Too many cooks.
听我一句  作为一个大老爷们儿
Take it from me. As a grown boy,
你只需要按时出席婚礼并说对名字即可
all you have to do is show up and try to say the right name.
-天啊那是什么  -天  婚礼手册
- What in God's name is that? - Oh, my God, the wedding book?
4年级以后就没见过它啊
I haven't seen that since fourth grade.
这本手册里面有所有信息
This baby has got everything.
就拿婚礼地点举例吧
Take, you know, locations, for instance,
首先按照字母顺序排列  再按地理位置排
first organized alphabetically, then geographically...
再按占地面积排
...then by square footage.
好聪明
That is so smart.
别掺和  赶紧走
Break it off. Break it off now.
这可以充分证明
That conclusively proves...
《侏罗纪公园》的灵感是我先有的
...that I had the idea for Jurassic Park first.
我们来看看
Let's take a look...
菲比  你来干什么
Phoebe, what are you doing here?
我有事和你说  很紧急
I need to talk to you. It's urgent.
有关莫妮卡和钱德
It's about Monica and Chandler.
我的天  当然
Oh, my God. Of course.
我失陪一下
Would you please excuse me for a moment?
你们知道彼此从哪儿来的吗   何不
Do you know each other's hometowns? Why don't you...?
怎么回事
What's going on?
没什么  但是
Well, not much. But...
我想他们刚订婚
I was just thinking that since they just got engaged...
应该多给他们一些独处的时间
...it would be nice if they have privacy.
我可以搬去你家住几天吗
So could I just move in with you for a couple days?
好  但莫妮卡和钱德勒怎么了
Okay, sure. But what's wrong with Monica and Chandler?
没事  怎么了
Nothing. Why?
你说很紧急的
Phoebe, you said it was urgent.
是啊  我的电影5分钟后要开演了
Yeah, it is. My movie starts in, like, five minutes.
你知道我有一屋子的学生在这儿吗
Do you realize I have a classroom full of students?
抱歉  我太失礼了
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm so rude.
有人想要一起去看电影吗
Does anyone want to come to the movies?
我还没和我爸妈讲清楚预算
I haven't cleared the budget with my parents...
不过音乐部份的安排这样好不好
...but tell me how this is for music,
入场时用弦乐四重奏
A string quartet for the processional,
鸡尾酒会时安排爵士乐三重奏
a jazz trio for cocktails...
跳舞时用湾市摇滚
...the Bay City Rollers for dancing...
慢着  那是我六年级婚礼的计划
Wait, that was for my sixth grade wedding.
怎样都不会成行了
You couldn't get them anyway.
伊恩不演出了  德瑞克
Lan doesn't even play anymore and Derek...
我不该知道德瑞克这个人的
Derek is a name I shouldn't know.
莫妮卡  有抱起来更舒服一点的枕头吗
Mon, do you have another pillow, something a little snugglier?
你为什么不回去你家  要在这里睡
Why are you napping over here instead of at your place?
-因为阿鸭 -什么  阿鸭
- The duck. - What... the duck?
那该死的阿鸭又做了什么
What the hell did the damn duck do now?
它没有到处吐
Well, he did not get sick somewhere in there...
它立刻被发现  并妥当处理干净了
...and it was immediately found and properly cleaned up.
我可以看吗
Do I get to look at this book...
还是只有婚礼相关人员可以看
...or is it just for people involved in the wedding?
你当然可以看  我也需要你的意见
Of course you can look at it. I want your opinion too.
来
Here you go.
-桌子中间的花饰呢  -花饰
- What about centerpieces? - Centerpieces!
-玫瑰还是百合  -绝对玫瑰
- Roses or lilies? - Definitely roses.
更有婚礼气氛
I think they're more "Wedding-y."
但明显应该选百合
But lilies are the clear choice.
天啊  心有灵犀
Oh, my God, it's like one mind.
各位  各位  让我休息好不好
Guys, guys, you gotta let me nap.
不然我会脾气不好
I'm gonna get cranky.
乔伊  走廊对面有极舒服的沙发
Joey, there's a perfectly good couch across the hall.
是很不错
Yes, it is perfectly good...
但阿鸭没在上面吐过
...and it is not one of the places the duck got sick.
什么
What?
-我要走了 -乔伊  阿鸭到底做了什么
- All right, I'm gonna go. - Joey, what did the duck do?
我不知道  但它没吃你的面霜
I don't know, but he did not eat your face cream.
小朋友  你觉得如何
Hey, little buddy. How you feeling?
那面霜里到底有什么
What the hell is in that face cream?
好软
That's so soft.
有枕头套耶
Pillowcases!
"柔达看着扫烟囱的人 她的父亲是个传教士"
"Zelda looked at the chimney sweep. Her father, the vicar..."
传教士
Vicar?
"还有好几小时才回家
"...wouldn't be home for hours.
她欲火中烧
Her loins were burning.
她不顾一切伸出手去抓住他的"
She threw caution to the wind and reached out and grabbed his..."
小黄书
This is a dirty book!
菲比
Phoebe?
罗斯  你好啊
Oh, Ross, hi.
菲比  你在干什么
Phoebe, what are you doing?
抱歉  我有客户在
Sorry, I'm with a client right now.
-菲比   -好吧  我们在外面谈
- Phoebe! - Okay, let's talk outside.
你不可以在我家帮人按摩
Phoebe, you can't massage people in my apartment.
我在莫妮卡和钱德家都可以
Same thing I did at Monica and Chandler's.
他们知道吗
And they knew about it?
好吧  罗斯  到底怎么回事
Okay, Ross, what is this really about?
这是我家  我希望能自由出入
This is my home and I want to be able to come and go whenever I want.
我会另找地方
I will find someplace else to do the rest of my appointments.
不明白有什么好大惊小怪的
I don't know what the big deal is.
我不要光着身子身上油油的陌生人在我家
The big deal is I don't want naked, greasy strangers in my apartment...
当我想拿一片拼图  我是说一瓶冰啤酒
...when I want to kick back with a puzzle... Beer, cold beer.
乔伊  你好吗
Hey, Joey. What are you doing?
在扫地  怎么   引起你的性趣吗
Sweeping. Why? Does it turn you on?
没
No.
如果我扫的是烟囱呢
What if I was sweeping a chimney?
乔伊  吃我面霜的其实是你吗
Joey, did you eat my face cream?
你去哪儿   传教士要几小时后才会回家
Where are you going? The vicar won't be home for hours.
乔伊  你从哪儿学到传教士这个词的
Joey, where did you learn that word?
你觉得呢
Where do you think...
柔达
...Zelda?
-你看了我的书   -对
- You found my book?! - Yeah, I did!
乔伊  你到我卧室里干什么
Joey, what are you doing going into my bedroom?
抱歉我去小睡一下
I'm sorry. I went in there to take a nap.
我知道我不应该  但是你有小黄书
I know I shouldn't have, but you got porn!
我不在乎 我不觉得我的书丢脸
You know what? I don't care. I'm not ashamed of my book.
女人享受一点情色没什么不对
There's nothing wrong with a woman enjoying a little erotica.
是女性对性爱健康的表达
It's just a healthy expression of female sexuality...
顺便说一句
...which, by the way,
你永远都不会理解的
is something that you will never understand.
你有小黄书
You got porn.
-你好  -嗨  菲比在吗
- Hello. - Hi, is Phoebe here?
-不  今晚她不在 -真是的
- No, she's out for the night. - Oh, great.
有什么我可以帮忙的吗
Can I help you with something?
我不知道  你是按摩师吗
I don't know. Are you a masseur?
我是
Yes, I am.
太好了  爸
Great! Dad?
谢谢你  一小时后我来接他
Thank you so much. I'll be back and pick him up in an hour.
要我帮你吗
You need help with that?
你父母听到你订婚
Your parents must've been
一定很激动
thrilled when you told them you were engaged.
对啊  我还真应该给他们打个电话
Oh, yeah. I should probably call them.
我还记得我们刚订婚的时候
I remember when we first got engaged.
-我没听过这个故事 -爸  你不要
- I don't think I've never heard that story. - Dad, you don't...
朱迪被我弄大了肚子
Well, I'd gotten Judy pregnant.
我还是不知道是怎么发生的
I still don't know how that happened.
你不知道   你的狗以为避孕器是磨牙玩具
You don't know how that happened? Your dog thought my diaphragm was a chew toy.
这故事真感人
What a sweet story.
至少你不是在
At least you're not hearing
五年级的万圣节派对听到这故事的
it at your fifth grade Halloween party.
他们当时说要听吓人的故事
They wanted a scary story.
我们对婚礼有很多激动人心的设想
We're really excited about our wedding plans.
很快我们就要
I guess pretty soon we'll be
从莫妮卡婚礼基金提一大笔钱
making a big withdrawal from the Monica wedding fund.
-什么  -杰克你说  我开不了口
- What? - You tell her, Jack. I can't do it.
你们有莫妮卡婚礼基金  对吧
You have the Monica wedding fund, don't you?
有  但是现在我们管它叫"海滩别墅"
We have it. Only, now we call it "The beach house."
你用我的婚礼基金买海滩别墅了
I can't believe it you spent my wedding fund on the beach house?
对不起  我们以为
We're sorry honey. We assumed...
如果你30岁以后结婚  你会自己付钱
...that if you got married after 30 you'd pay for it yourself.
你们买海滩别墅时我才23岁
You bought the beach house when I was 23.
你在海滩享受了7年好时光
So you've had seven years of beach fun...
宝贝儿  那可是无价的
...and you can't put a price on that sweetie.
我们很抱歉
We really do feel bad about this.
你和理查德交往的时候我们又开始存钱了
We saved again when you dated Richard...
后来你们分手了  我们就重新装修了厨房
...then that went to hell, so we redid the kitchen.
那我和钱德勒约会的时候呢
What about me dating Chandler?
我们没觉得他会向你求婚
It was Chandler. We didn't think he'd propose.
明显刚吃饭时  我的酒喝得不够
Clearly I did not start drinking enough at the start of the meal.
我不相信我的婚礼基金竟然没了
I can't believe there's no money for my wedding.
我们本来还有钱  要不是你爸
We might still have some money, if your father hadn't tried...
在网上卖冰毒的话
...to sell ice over the Internet.
那看起来很简单
It seemed like such a simple idea.
是愚蠢  杰克  不是简单是愚蠢
Stupid, Jack. The word is stupid.
够了  我不想再听了
Enough. I don't want to hear about it anymore.
钱德勒  祝你好运
Good luck, Chandler.
我就要
Okay, now I'm going to...
碰你了
...touch you.
好软
That's soft.
你父母可能帮忙付钱吗
Do you think your parents could help pay for it?
不知道
I don't know.
我妈大部份的钱都花在她第四次的婚礼了
My mother spent most of her money on her fourth wedding.
剩下的钱她离婚要用
She's saving the rest for her divorce.
而我爸存的钱
And any extra cash my
都花在他每年一度的桃利主题公园
father has he saves for his yearly trips to...
之旅上了[艳星桃利·伯顿主题公园]
...Dollywood.
-你们饭吃得如何  -我父母把婚礼基金花掉了
- What happened at dinner? - My parents spent the money for our wedding.
天  你是点了什么菜
My God, what did you order?
等一下  没有婚礼基金   太惨了
Wait, there's no money? Well, this is terrible.
你们俩得去  健身房结婚了
You guys are gonna have to get married in, like, a rec center.
-亲爱的会没事的  -才不会  这太惨了
- Honey, it's gonna be okay - No, it's not gonna be okay. It sucks.
没有拉风的乐队没有百合
No swing band, no lilies. -
没事的
You know what It's gonna be okay.
你不需要这种
I mean, you don't need to have this...
意大利乡村盛飨
...rustic Italian feast.
你不需要这种订做的
You know, you don't need this custom-made...
英式腰线  公爵夫人式礼服
...empire-waisted, duchess satin gown.
你可以买现成的
You can wear off-the-rack.
没事的
It's really gonna be okay.
重要的是
The important thing is that
我们彼此相爱  要结婚了
we love each other and we're gonna get married.
你知不知道"现成的"是什么意思
Do you even understand what "Off-the-rack" means?
你为什么不自己付钱呢
Why don't you pay for it yourself?
怎么付  我没钱
How? I don't have any money.
-我有  -多少
- Well, I have some. - How much?
将近有
Well, close to...
-你开玩笑  -多少
- Are you kidding me?! - How much is it?
-够办A式婚礼 -真的
- Enough for wedding scenario A. - Really?
你真好  努力存钱的人
How great are you, you little saver!
这正是理想婚礼的预算
This is exactly the budget of my dream wedding.
你们是天造地设的一对
You guys are so made for each other.
你不是要
You're not suggesting that
把所有的钱都花在婚礼上吧
we spend all of the money on the wedding?
是啊
Yeah.
我花了六年才存了
Look, Mon, I've been saving this money for six years...
有些是将来要用的
...and I kind of had some of
能都花在一场派对上
it earmarked for the future, not just for a party.
嗨  钱德勒先生
Hello, Mr. Chandler.
亲爱的  这是我们一生中最重要的一天
Sweetie, this is the most special day of our lives.
我知道亲爱的  但
I realize that, honey, but
但我不要把钱都花在一场派对上
I'm not gonna spend all the money on one party.
亲爱的  我爱你
Honey, I love you.
但你要是再把我们的婚礼叫做派对
But if you call our wedding a party one more time...
我就不请你了哟
...you may not get invited.
钱可以再赚  我们只结婚一次
We can always earn more money. We're only gonna get married once.
我了解  但我非常坚决  我的答案是不
I understand, but I have to put my foot down. The answer is no.
你很坚决
You're gonna have to "Put your foot down"?
对
Yes, I am.
有钱又坚定
Money and a firm hand.
钱德勒终于变成了我可以共事的人了
Finally a Chandler I can get on board with.
-嗨瑞秋  -乔伊
- Hey, Rach. - Joey.
闻到烟味了吗
Hey, Rach, do you smell smoke?
我懂了  烟味烟囱  扫烟囱  幽默
I get it. Smoke, chimney, chimney sweep. Very funny. Ha, ha.
不  我说真的  你没闻到吗
No, no, I'm serious. You don't smell it?
有东西着火了
Something's on fire.
我没闻到
No, I don't smell anything.
可能是你熊熊的欲火
Oh, you know what? It's probably just your burning loins.
-你们在讲什么   -没什么
- Hey, what are you guys talking about? - Nothing.
讨厌  咖啡冷了
Damn, this coffee's cold.
介意用你的欲火为我加热一下吗
Do you mind if I heat this up on your loins?
乔伊  你竟然告诉他了
You know, I cannot believe you told him. Joey...
我猜你在我们分手后买了那本书
So I guess you bought that book after we broke up.
是啊
Yeah, I did, because I
因为第一本在我们交往时被翻烂了
wore out my first copy when I was with you.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
我们交往时  我看了一大堆色情杂志
Well, when we were going out, I read tons of porno magazines.
怎样
What's up?
罗斯  你怎么能对个老人那样呢
Ross, how could you do that to an old man?
对不起  小姐们
Excuse me, ladies.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
我的按摩客户  亚瑟
My massage client, Arthur.
他女儿说我的一个员工
His daughter said some guy that worked for me...
替他做了很奇怪的按摩
...gave him a really weird massage.
我做了很专业的按摩
I gave him an extremely professional massage.
他说你用木汤匙戳他
He said you poked at him with wooden spoons.
好吧  不是传统的按摩
Okay, so it wasn't a traditional massage.
可是我有用筷子为他指压按摩
But I did give him acupressure with a pair of chopsticks...
并温和地用抹布给他去了角质
...and I gently exfoliated him with a mop.
他再也不会来了 你害我一星期少进帐八十元
Well, he's never coming back. You just cost me $80 a week.
是你的错  你没更改他约的时间
This is your fault. You didn't move his appointment.
我的错  你不必替他按摩的
Oh, it's my fault? You didn't have to massage him.
你可以打发他走的
You could've sent him away.
你不用拿玩具唐卡车在他背上滚来滚去的
You could've not rolled Tonka trucks up and down his back.
他说他很喜欢的
He said he liked that!
你说得对  抱歉
You're right, you're right. I'm sorry.
你干嘛按摩一位老先生
Dude, what are you massaging an old man for?
-他女儿超性感 -懂了
- His daughter was hot. - Gotcha.
听着
Listen...
我想过了
...l've been thinking.
要你把所有的钱
It's not fair of me to ask you
都花在婚礼上很不公平
to spend all of your money on our wedding.
你很辛苦才赚来的
I mean, you work really hard for that.
-好吧  -好吧  你赚来的
- Well. - Well, you work for that.
我也想过了
Look, I've thought about it too.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我觉得我们应该把钱花在婚礼上的
I think we should spend all of the money on the wedding.
-真的  -对  我很坚定
- You do? - Yeah, I'm putting my foot down.
当我求婚时  我告诉你
Look, when I proposed, I told you...
我会尽我所能让你快乐
...that I would do anything to make you happy.
如果办一场完美的婚礼能让你开心
And if having the perfect wedding makes you happy...
那就这么做吧
...then that's what we're gonna do.
你太好了
You are so sweet.
那未来呢
What about the future and stuff?
管他呢
Forget about the future and stuff.
我们只生两个就好
So we only have two kids.
选一个我们喜欢的让他去念大学
We'll pick our favorite and that one will get to go to college.
-你想过这些  -对
- Have you thought about that? - Yeah.
你本来要几个孩子
How many kids were we gonna have?
四个  一个男孩一对双胞胎女儿  再一个男孩
Four. A boy, twin girls and another boy.
你还想过什么
What else did you think about?
我们将来住哪
Well, stuff like where we'd live, you know.
市郊的小房子之类的
Like a small place outside the city...
我们的小孩可以在那里学骑单车
...where our kids could learn to ride their bikes.
以养只猫  脖子上挂着铃档
We could have a cat that had a bell on its collar...
这样每次它跑出小门
...and we could hear it every time
我们就听得见铃声
it ran through the little kitty door.
在车库上盖个房间  让乔伊养老
We'd have an apartment over the garage where Joey could grow old.
你知道吗
You know what?
我不想要一个盛大的婚礼了
I don't want a big, fancy wedding.
-你当然想  -不
- Sure you do. - No.
我要你刚刚说的每一样 我要婚姻
I want everything that you've just said. I want a marriage.
你确定
You sure?
-我好爱你  -我爱你
- I love you so much. - I love you.
你刚说起未来的时候  谈到猫
When you were talking about our future, you said cat.
你指的是狗  对不对
But you meant dog, right?
-对  -太好了
- Yeah, totally. - Oh, good.
你好啊  柔达
Hello, Zelda.
-你要扮谁啊   -传教士
- Who are you supposed to be? - The vicar.
-你知道传教士是什么人吗  -守门员那种人嘛
- Do you even know what a vicar is? - Like a goalie, right?
够了
Look, that's enough.
你讲那个愚蠢的笑话  含沙射影
You make stupid jokes and sleazy innuendoes...
一点都不好笑
...and it's just not funny anymore.
对不起  瑞秋  对不起
I'm sorry. Rach, I'm sorry.
也许我可以用带你去谷仓
Maybe I could make it up to you
来场粗野的弥补你一下
by taking you roughly in the barn.
行了  你想做  那就做吧
All right, that's it. You wanna do it? Let's do it.
没错  就跟你
That's right. I wanna do it with you.
一直都试图抵抗  但你刚才的话彻底地燃起了我的欲火
Been trying to fight it, but you just said all the right things.
我说的话
I did?
对  为了蹂躏你那小身子板我等待了多时
Yeah. Oh, I've been waiting so long to get on that body.
-我的小身子板  -对
- This body? - Yeah, that's right.
来啊  乔伊  燃烧我吧
Come on, Joey, sex me up.
你听起来像
You're starting to sound like
第7章里屠夫的老婆
the butcher's wife in chapter seven.
来吧  别让我等了  脱衣服
Come on, now. Don't keep me waiting. Get those clothes off.
头盔留着  因为这将是粗野之旅
But I'd keep that helmet on, because you're in for a rough ride.
我不要  我好怕
I don't want to. I'm scared.